Kingdom come deliverance is probably the most historically accurate game about rural 15th century Bohemia this year
Although, I am not sure
Now, I don't have a PHD in history, I can't even read
But... Uh, I was there!
I met all of these people in real life, and this game got everything wrong
Quick sidenote: I have seen some Yanks confuse where this game takes place
It's not Germany or the kingdom of the Magyars
The game's setting is Czechoslovakia
And before you say "Czechoslovakia does not exist anymore"
Yeah
It's an historical game, this is why you need me to explain everything
Also, I have a lot of Czech viewers
Or at least I had before I made this video
But I don't want to lose the rest of them
So from now on, no more jokes about the Czechs
So, is Kingdom Come Deliverance really historically accurate?
Let's begin with the game's story
Elder scrolls Bohemia actually starts with summing up the events prior to the game
I can too!
Dude named Charles ruled and he built a bridge and people liked him
Then he died and his son...
Vækkislækkifour
Took over
It's the Czech pronounciation
But the German Aristocracy did not like him because of his weird name
Then Siggisman showed up, who had a less weird name
So they joined him
I know, I know. Finally a game where Germans are the villains
Then we are introduced to the main character
This is Henry
[Bell sound]
No, I have already made a historical video about a guy named Henry
I'm gonna have to give him a traditional Czech name
This is Pilsner
[Bell sound]
He's not some foretold hero, he's a nobody
And very, very dumb
The game have been praised for that, people say it's refreshing
But, it's not historically accurate
If you look up Henry of Skalitz on Wikipedia
It clearly states that he was the chosen one
And had like seven prophecies writte about him
And could totes use magic and shit
The game tells the story of him becoming a knight
But the real guy saved the world from an ancient evil
I think the only thing the story gets correct is that they all spoke British English
So, what about the gameplay?
Apparently they used thousands of hours researching sword combat
What a waste of time, I used a Mace
Or a Bow
When you hit someone with the bow they don't instantly die, like in those three documentaries
And it's hard to aim
In one quest you go into the forest to "capture" rabbits and it's impossible to hit the damn things
Yet the truth is, if I went into a forest with a bow I would catch 0 rabbits
Which makes this super unrealistic
You can then cook the rabbit, back in medieval europe you had to eat food; or you would die
There are no hamburgers or Pizza Huts
Because they didn't actually have those
The only people that did were time travelers
Hollywood has made it look like there were time travelers everywhere
But in reality they were pretty rare
Cooking though is just a hobby, you are really supposed to walk into strangers' houses and eat from their pot
We know this is something that really happened, because I still do this today
Another art mimic real life moment
In one quest you are required to read a book
And if you misread it, an entire village dies
This also happened to me
But that was yesterday, so I've gotten over it
All in all, gameplay got some stuff right.
Finally, the setting
The most historically authentic game before this was return of the king
On XBox 1
But that takes place in Middle Earth, and this is Germany or Hungary
Honestly though, besides the orcs and the weed, they are pretty similar
The clothing is very accurate, this is how all Slavs looked like before the invention of the tracksuit
But I have researched everywhere and I haven't found these clothes
I can't find any proof they made clothing that looked like a texture glitch
They completly messed up the animals
Many medieval stories reference dragons, but there are no dragons
Worst though, is that the Bohemian Coat of Arms has a lion
But there are no wild lions with cute crowns
That's a huge oversight
And obviously the developers can't do anything for us to smell the smell
So for extra immersion I played the game in an outhouse
And whoever was there before me did the designers a huge favor
Final conclusion: They did not use fire arrows
Zero out of one hundred!
Literally unplayable!
[WTF, why did he replace Ricedy Roadster with this Yuletide song???]